Junyi Zhang

■ junyizhang@sjtu.edu.cn ♦ Junyi42 ♦ junyi42.com

Research interests

My research interests mainly lie in computer vision, deep generative models, and representation learning. I am now focusing on the application of diffusion models, exploring its potential for both generation and perception scenarios. I also have a background in action recognition, self-supervised learning, and other modalities including video, 3D, human motion, and language.

EDUCATION

SEIEE, Shanghai Jiao Tong University

Shanghai, China

Major in Computer Science and Technology, GPA: 3.92 (8/108)

Sept. 2020 - Present

Zhiyuan College, Shanghai Jiao Tong University

Major in Zhiyuan Honors Program of Engineering (Top 5%)

SELECTED AWARDS

Microsoft Research "Stars of Tomorrow" Certificate (Top 10% interns)

2022

Huawei Fellowship (Top 1% in honors program)

National Scholarship (Top 0.2% nationwide, highest honor in China)

2021

Outstanding Undergraduate Scholarship, A Level, SJTU (Top 1%)

Publications 1 4 1

A Tale of Two Features: Stable Diffusion Complements DINO for Zero-Shot Semantic Correspondence Junyi Zhang, Charles Herrmann, Junhwa Hur, Luisa F. Polanía, Varun Jampani, Deqing Sun, Ming-Hsuan Yang. NeurIPS, 2023. [Webpage] [Code] [ArXiv]

Layout Diffusion: Improving Graphic Layout Generation by Discrete Diffusion Probabilistic Models Junyi Zhang, Jiaqi Guo, Shizhao Sun, Jian-Guang Lou, Dongmei Zhang.

ICCV, 2023. [Code] [ArXiv]

From Isolated Islands to Pangea: Unifying Semantic Space for Human Action Understanding

Yong-Lu Li*, Xiaoqian Wu*, Xinpeng Liu, Yiming Dou, Yikun Ji, Junyi Zhang, Yixing Li, Xudong Lu, Jingru Tan, Cewu Lu. Under review, 2023. [Webpage] [ArXiv]

Mining Cross-Person Cues for Body-Part Interactiveness Learning in HOI Detection

Xiaoqian Wu*, Yong-Lu Li*, Xinpeng Liu, Junyi Zhang, Yuzhe Wu, Cewu Lu.

ECCV, 2022. [Code] [ArXiv]

EXPERIENCE

University of California, Merced - Vision Learning Lab

Merced, California

Visiting Student – Supervisor: *Prof.* Ming-Hsuan Yang

June 2023 - Present

• Explore diffusion representations for semantic correspondence

Microsoft Research Asia - Data, Knowledge and Intelligence Group

Beijing, China

Research Intern – Mentor: Dr. Shizhao Sun and Dr. Jian-Guang Lou

July 2022 - Dec. 2022

• Build discrete diffusion models for layout synthesis

Shanghai Jiao Tong University - Machine Vision and Intelligence Group

Shanghai, China Oct. 2021 - Present

Undergraduate Research Intern – Supervisor: *Prof.* Yong-Lu Li

• Build diffusion models for interactive motion generation

- Experiment on extending multimodal action recognition to video dataset
- Experiment on incorporating human knowledge into HOI detection

SKILLS

- Skills: Python (Pytorch), C/C++, html, css, Linux, LATEX, Assembly language
- Languages: English (TOEFL 105/120), Chinese (Native)

REFERENCES

- Ming-Hsuan Yang, Professor of EECS University of California, Merced; Research Scientist, Google Research
- Deqing Sun, Research Scientist, Google Research
- Varun Jampani, Research Scientist, Google Research
- Charles Herrmann, Research Scientist, Google Research
- Junhwa Hur, Research Scientist, Google Research
- Jian-Guang Lou, Principal Researcher, Microsoft Research
- Shizhao Sun, Senior Researcher, Microsoft Research
- Yong-Lu Li, Assistant Professor of Computer Science Shanghai Jiao Tong University